Bruce Russell Papers
Bruce Russell Papers
- Original drawings
  - By Bruce Russell
    - Editorial cartoons
      - E, 1957-1958; 1961-1963,; undated (Oversize 13)
        East Berlin? Got any extra bricks and barbed wire? (Aug. 19 1961)
        Eat, drink and be wary (March 8 1962)
        Emmy nomination for endurance (May 2 1963)
        End of the trial (Dec. 12 1961)
        An epitaph that's becoming more and more common (Feb. 1 1958)
        Equal partners (undated)
        The European shell game! (undated)
        Every new car has an old style satellite (Nov. 18 1957)
        Eyesocket to eyesocket (July 20 1963)
      - F, 1960; 1963,; undated (Oversize 13)
        The 'Face the Russian Nation' program (Oct. 15 1960)
        The farmer in the dell (undated)
        Featherbedding deluxe...with maid service (Aug. 3 1963)
        The flower barrel (undated)
        Foot of clay (April 1 1963)
        The fourth at bridge! (undated)
        Frankenstein! (undated)
        Fright farmer (May 31 1963)
      - G, 1962; undated (Oversize 14)
        The gargoyle (Aug. 6 1962)
        Gazing into the decreasing roll! (undated)
        Gonna take a lot of rope, Jack! (1962)
        The grade's been made without a slip! (undated )
      - H, 1929; 1935,; 1951,; 1957-1958,; 1962-1963,; undated (Oversize 14)
        He can't be Napoleon Bonaparte--I'm Napoleon Bonaparte! (Nov. 1 1957)
        He didn't even get to first base! (1929?)
        He looks like a good dancer! (undated)
        He only eats once a year, but--! (undated)
        He wants to blow his own horn! (undated)
        The head man (undated)
        Heck, quints aren't unusual! (Sept. 21 1963)
        Here comes THE ambassador! (undated)
        Here, put these on, you guys (Oct. 25 1963)
        Herein lies Ethiopia! (circa 1935)
        He's putting on a show for us! (undated)
        The higher gov't costs ledge (May 28 1963)
        His "bridges" to dreamland (Sept. 21 1958)
        His entry! (undated)
        Hm! Stealing my stuff! (undated)
        Hole in his stocking (Dec. 11 1962)
        Homage ([1929])
        How now, brown cow (Feb. 8 1951)
        How old fashioned! (undated)
        How to assure the proof of the pudding (undated)
        How to rope a fight mare? (Jan. 23 1962)
      - I, 1930; 1937,; 1952,; 1956-1957,; 1960,; 1962-1963,; undated (Oversize 14)
        "If wishbones were horses!" (undated)
        "If you drink up and drive up--" (Dec 21 1960)
        "Ike's ark" (Sep. 20 1956)
        "I'll see you in 1938" (1937?)
        "In case of fire, keep cool!"(fire prevention week) (Oct 6)
        [Income balancing act] (Mar 2, 1937)
        [Inflation couch] (undated)
        "In hoc, signo vinces" (undated)
        "In the national unity cornfield" (Mar 9 1962)
        "In pursuit of the shooting dollar" (Mar 9 1957)
        "Indian sign" (Nov. 16 1963)
        "It used to be an exclusive business!" (undated)
        "It will just be a question of weight!" (undated)
        "It would be a dull day indeed" (undated)
        "It's a plate cracker!" (undated)
        "It's a round trip" (undated)
        "It's an old Southern costume" (Mar. 1 1952)
        "It's changed bearers!" (circa 1930)
      - I, 1958 (Oversize 11)
        "If we get some ham, well have some ham and eggs--and we will get eggs." (Oct 20 1958)
      - I, 1937; undated; ink on heavy board (Oversize 12)
        [income balancing act] (Mar. 2 1937)
      - J, 1930; undated (Oversize 14)
        "Jack and the means talk" (undated)
        "Jack Sprat and wife!" (undated)
        "John's bull!" (undated)
        "Just from one piece of paper!" (circa 1930)
      - K, circa 1929 (Oversize 14)
        "The key to the cellar" (circa 1929)
      - L, 1928; 1956,; 1960,; undated (Oversize 14)
        "Landing strip" (Dec. 17 1960)
        "The leading publisher" (undated)
        "Let me look into it.!" (undated)
        "Let's stuff this ballot box" (undated)
        "The lines of March" ([1928])
        "The line's still busy" (undated)
        "The low, low form of Homo sapiens" (Dec. 29 1956)
        "The lowest thing on earth" (undated)
      - M, 1954-1957; 1961-1962,; undated (Oversize 15)
        "Mahomet comes to the mountain" (undated)
        "Mahomet isn't going anywhere" (Nov. 15 1962)
        "The Maine stein song" (Sept. 15 1954)
        "Maybe we forgot the most important one of all" (July 25 1955)
        "Me, too!" (undated)
        "Measuring them up early" (undated)
        "Merry Christmas--" (undated)
        "Middle East, date line" (Nov. 11 1956)
        "Milwaukee's orbit!" (Oct. 11 1957)
        "Moonlight an the Ganges" (Dec. 19 1961)
        "More baking power'" (undated)
        "More spring training!" (undated)
        "My figure's improving!" (undated)
      - N, 1955; 1959,; 1962-1963,; undated (Oversize 15)
        "National contract, national velvet!" (Nov. 18 1963)
        "Needed -- a moratorium on this death penalty!" (Jan. 12, 1963)
        "New frontier image" (Feb. 23, 1963)
        "New Hampshire dollar" (May 5 1963)
        "The new hat" (undated)
        "New mirage in the Stassen desert" (March 8 1959)
        "The new moon and the shadow!" (undated)
        "New Royal Canadian Mounted" (July 3 1962)
        "The new savings account" (undated)
        "Neither dead nor in the red" (Jan. 2 1962)
        "No exchanges" (Dec. 28 1955)
        "Not much time for him!" (undated)
      - O, 1930; 1956,; 1961-1963,; undated (Oversize 15)
        "Of course we are" (circa 1930)
        "Old McDonald had a farm" (undated)
        "Ole Mess" (Oct. 7 1962)
        "Only one day more!" (undated)
        "Our financial cousin" (April 7 1963)
        "Our man in Havana" (Sept. 16 1962)
        "Our man of the year, every year" (Dec. 29 1961)
        "Our two constant companions" (Sept. 21 1956)
        "Out of the ashes" (undated)
        "Overhanging cliff and rising tide" (May 13 1963)
      - P, 1958; 1961-1962,; undated (Oversize 15)
        "Passing the baton" (undated)
        "Perch-mates!" (undated)
        "Perjurer's hour" (Nov. 13 1962)
        "Pie in the sky and the pie plate" (Oct. 15 1958)
        "Ping along with Mich." (Feb. 14 1962)
        "The pit and the pendulum!" (undated)
        "Plunk!" (undated)
        "Practice Ground for Three Chop Sticks?" (undated) - gift of Robert Payne, 2009
        "Public menace no. 1" (Jan 8 1961)
      - R, 1930; 1955,; 1957,; 1960-1963,; undated (Oversize 15)
        "The rain of law" (undated)
        "Ran into a fender" (Aug. 17 1961)
        "Readin', 'ritin', 'rithmetic, and remote control" (Feb. 11 1962)
        "Relegated to the New Frontier museum"(government spending) (Aug. 27 1962)
        "Remember now, no fishing" (undated)
        "Renewal tab (Feb.3 1957)
        "Returned to sender" (Mar. 11 1960)
        "A right and a left!" (undated)
        "A ring full" (undated)
        "Ringers" (Dec. 1930)
        "The routes to conquer our educational Everest" (May 25 1963)
        "Russian spelling" (Sept. 8 1955)
      - R, 1958 (Oversize 11)
        "Recklessness pitching" (Apr 21 1958)
      - S, 1931; 1954,; 1956,; 1960,; 1962,; undated (Oversize 16)
        "Santa Claus with an empty bag" (Dec. 3 1962)
        "The school 'go!' " (undated)
        "Sewer gas" (Apr 2 1962)
        "Silenced" (death of Nicholas Longworth) (1931)
        "Simmer school" (Jul 17 1954)
        "So goes the tortoise" (Sept 12 1956)
        "Somebody's always standing with a pin!" (undated)
        "Sonny, are you serious?" (undated)
        "Still figuring" (undated)
        "The stop sign of prevention" (Jan 4 1954)
        "Strike one!" (undated)
        "Studio lot" (Feb 13 1960)
        "The swatting season" (undated)
      - S, 1958; 1961-1962 (Oversize 11)
        "The seasons" (Oct 14 1961)
        "Self-framed" (Apr 7 1962)
        "Stop sign" (Jan 20 1958)
      - T, 1939; 1955-1958,; 1960,; 1962-1963,; undated (Oversize 16)
        "Tailor made" (Sep 5 1962)
        "Test ban concessions extra nice today, sir!" (Aug 10 1962)
        "Test for a test ban" (Jul 28 1963)
        "Testing 1-2-3-4-5-6-7" (Feb 2 1957)
        "There'll be no deep freezes or vicuna coats" (Oct 19 1960)
        "This gun for hire" (Mar 10 1955)
        "This is a dizzy old world!" (undated)
        "Those forbidden dances!" (circa 1939)
        "Those hard-to-crack 'after Easter' eggs" (Apr 16 1958)
        "Time for Mohammed to go to the mountain" (Apr 27 1957)
        "The toll of traffic" (undated)
        "Too bad our No. 1 murderer can't be put there" (Mar 23 1963)
        Two horses that can't be doped" (undated)
        "Two soles with but a single thought" (Oct 28 1956)
        "Typical backing for backing a red" (undated)
      - T, 1959; undated (Oversize 11)
        "Teacher's pet" (Mar 2 1959)
        Traffic 3-D" (undated)
      - U, 1963; undated (Oversize 16)
        "Up we go into the high blue yonder" (Aug 31 1963)
        "Upholding Hitler's military policy!" (undated)
      - W, 1959; 1961,; undated (Oversize 16)
        "The Washington 'wide open'" (undated)
        "Welcome to the club, Tom" (Apr 30 1959)
        "We're running a high temperature!" (undated)
        "What are we going to do about this auto strike?" (undated)
        "What does that last line say?" (undated)
        "What this country needs is another Lincoln!" (undated)
        "What to do with your old hat" (Mar 24)
        "What's your hurry?" (undated)
        "When doctors disagree" (undated)
        "Where we hang our economy hat" (undated)
        "Where's that strike ointment" (Jul 5)
        "Who said there's safety in numbers?" (undated)
        "Who was that lady I saw you with last night?" (undated)
        "Wind it up and it becomes lethal" (undated)
        "Wonder, sometimes, if I'm getting any signals out" (Mar 3 1959)
        "Won't be anyone left to sign a separate peace" (Aug 7 1961)
        "A worthy setting" (undated)
      - Y, 1960; 1962-1963,; undated (Oversize 16)
        "Yep, everybody's in great form!" (Apr 13 1962)
        "Yep, the government must cut spending" (Nov 3 1963)
        "You and me both" (Oct 26 1963)
        "Your foot is getting too big for my mouth" (1960)
      - Z, 1956 (Oversize 16)
        "Zoning problem" (Sep 16 1956)
      - Untitled, 1961-1962 (Oversize 16)
        [Algerian peace] (1962)
        [employment] (1962)
        [Jimmy Hoffa] (Aug 30 1961)
    - Hollywood and theater illustrations, 1929; undated; 2 folders (Oversize 1)
    - Hollywood and theater illustrations, undated; 1 item (Oversize 11)
    - Los Angeles Times work
      - Cartoons, circa 1928 (Oversize 2)
      - Times Sunday Magazine covers, circa 1932; 3 panels (Oversize 2)
      - Miscellaneous illustrations, 1932; 1957,; undated (Oversize 2)
      - Miscellaneous illustrations, undated (Oversize 11)
    - Sports cartoons, undated; 5 items (Oversize 3)
    - Sports cartoons, Jul 30; 1 item (Oversize 11)
    - Fragments, undated (Box 25)
  - By others
    The following items are listed individually, but are not foldered individually. They are grouped by letter (e.g., "Original art by others, A-C").
    - Alley, Cal. "Sugar cured.", undated; editorial cartoon inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Baguez, Salvador. Untitled illustration (track runner), 9 Oct 1929; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Bardell, Wyn. Untitled illustration, undated (Oversize 9)
    - Bardell, Wyn. Untitled illustration (Hollywood?), undated (Oversize 16)
    - Barndollar, "Overcoming interference", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Barndollar, "Parking space", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Barndollar, "Red poppies", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Barndollar, (Russian marionettes), undated (Oversize 9)
    - Barndollar, "What more could one want?", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Barrow, Hank. "Trying to fill the bill" (world hunger), undated; editorial cartoon inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Bastian, Robert. "Anything you can do I can do louder" (atomic testing), 1960s; editorial cartoon inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Bastian, Robert. "Well, if you won't take it off, let's see what we can do with it on!" (hydrogen bomb tests), undated; editorial cartoon inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Batchelor, C.D. "A dad's idea of the perfect baby", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Bates, Bill. "Ping" strip, 1 Mar 1962; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Block, Herbert, See Herblock.
    - Bronstrup. "If bait counts, he's landed", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Cam, Billy. "If you are looking for somebody, you will find 'em out in Hollywood trying to get into the movies", undated; Pen and ink cartoon (Oversize 9)
    - Capp, Al. Untitled illustration with Li'l Abner characters, undated; "Drawn specially for the Los Angeles Times." (Oversize 9)
    - Carlisle, Tom. "There are no short cuts round the mountains.", undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 16)
    - Crawford, Bill. "They fly so high they touch the sky" (disarmament), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Crenshaw, George. "Orville drowns out the commercials.", 1958; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Criswell, Ralph. Untitled pen and ink illustration, undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Crockett, Gib. "Balkan serenade" (Tito)., May 15, no year; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Dalrymple, Louis. Untitled, undated; pen and ink illustration (Oversize 9)
    - Day, Robert. Untitled cartoon on Rube Wolf, 1927 (Oversize 9)
    - Day, Robert. Sunday Stage theater cartoon, undated (Oversize 16)
    - Day, Robert. "Yes, and we're doing most of the shaking", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Dodge, A.B. Untitled illustration, circa 1931; pen and ink, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Dodge, A.B. Untitled theater illustration, undated; pen and ink (Oversize 16)
    - Dowling, Dan. "Dr. Truman's message to the farmers" (farm vote), 11 Mar 1952; editorial cartoon inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Doyle, Jerry. Untitled editorial cartoon on Hitler, undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Ehrhart, S.D.. Untitled, 9 Dec 1903; pen and ink illustration (Oversize 11)
    - Egli, Leo. "And the sky's the limit", 1938 (Oversize 9)
    - Engelhardt, Tom. "Charmer" (Mme. Nhu), 1 Nov 1963; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Evans, Ray. "Relief--mostly for the politicians" (pork barrel projects), 31 May 1932; editorial cartoon, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Ewing, A.L. Untitled illustration, undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Ewing. Untitled drawing (metropolitan street scene), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell, (Oversize 9)
    - Ficklen, Herc."Walking man, European version" (Russia against Finland), 1939?; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Fischer, Jo. Untitled caricature, undated; pen and ink, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Fisher, Dudley T., Jr. "Jolly Jingles.", 6 Mar 1932; Oversized, colored panel. Inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 11)
    - Fitzpatrick, D.R. "Used to be ain't is" (U.S. China policy), 16 Jun 1957; editorial cartoon, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Flowers, Don. Untitled ink illustration, 1931; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Forsythe, Vic. "Little upset in plans", 1930; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 16)
    - Fox, Fontaine. "Mickey (Himself) McGuire", 1924; Single cartoon panel, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Fox, Fontaine. "Forty years ago--and now he's president" (Taft), 19 Feb 1909 (Oversize 9)
    - Gale, "Another ringside seat" (League of Nations vs. armaments), 1927; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Gale. "Is he coming out of lt?" (Bolshevism), undated (Oversize 9)
    - Gale. "The Knickerbocker Kids, No.3", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Gale. "The Knickerbocker Kids, No.4", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Gale. "The Knickerbocker Kids, No.5", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Gale. "The Knickerbocker Kids, No.6", undated (Oversize 9)
    - Gallaway. Untitled illustration, 15 Sep 1899; pen and ink (Oversize 16)
    - Garbatt. Untitled horse-racing illustration, undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Glackens, L.M. Untitled Puck illustration, 12 Mar 1907 (Oversize 9)
    - Goldberg, Rube. "Collared!" (The Cairo Plan against Japan), Jan 1944; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Goldberg, Rube. "They thrive an it" (dictators), Dec 1956; editorial cartoon, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Griffin, Sydney B. Untitled, 21 Sep 1891; pen and ink illustration (Oversize 9)
    - Hackney, Rick. Untitled (grassroots politics), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Hanny, William. "You can't trust a ball fan to do anything right" (baseball), circa 1915 (Oversize 9)
    - Hatlo, Jimmy. "They'll do it every time" (manners), undated; Single panel (Oversize 9)
    - Hatlo, Jimmy. "They'll do it every time." (a drunk), undated; single panel (Oversize 9)
    - Hatlo, Jimmy. "Dedicated to music week.", undated; Large panel, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Herblock. "Nightmare nostrum" (Mussolini), 18 Oct 1937?; inscribed to Bruce Russell, (Oversize 9)
    - Herblock. "Go away" (the Republicans' farm problem), 1955; inscribed to Joe Sherwood (Oversize 16)
    - Herriman, George. "Strangers outside the old gate.", undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Hitt, Oscar. "The merry widow.", 25 May 1931; colored cartoon panel, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Hix, Elsie. "Hix's strange as it seems.", 7 Sep 1949; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Hubenthal, Karl. Untitled (Red Chinese aggression), circa 1950; editorial cartoon inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 16)
    - Hubenthal, Karl. Untitled (Truman and MacArthur), 1951; editorial cartoon inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Hungerford, Cy. Caricature of Bruce Russell, undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 16)
    - Hungerford, Cy. "The champ loses his reputation.", undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Hutton, Hugh. Caricature of William Penn, undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 16)
    - Ireland. "Do I have to adopt that, too?" (Uncle Sam's dependencies), undated (Oversize 16)
    - Ivey, Jim. "No thanks--just looking" (Nixon), 3 Jan 1960 [1961?]; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Ivey, Jim. "'Chaff! " Straw in the wind'" (Richard Nixon and Pat Brown), undated (Oversize 9)
    - Ivey, Jim. "Chivalry is dead" (Goodwin Knight and Richard Nixon), 1962?; inscribed to Gov. Knight (Oversize 9)
    - Ivey, Jim. "The 'great-leap-forward'" (Chinese economic failures), 1960 (Oversize 9)
    - Ivey, Jim. "Happy birthday to you" (Berlin Wall), undated; "Pocket Cartoon" series (Oversize 9)
    - Ivey, Jim. "Nouveau riche" (Soviet space efforts), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Ivey, Jim. "Slowest gun in the West" (Kennedy), undated; "Pocket Cartoon" series (Oversize 9)
    - Ivey, Jim. Untitled cartoon (U.S. and Soviet Union space projects), 1962; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - Jenkins, Burris, Jr. Untitled (boxer Ben Jeby), undated (Oversize 10)
    - Jensen, Cecil. "Bad year for mosquitoes, ain't it?" (Hitler), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Knott, John. Untitled cartoon (hitchhiking conquistador), 1936; inscribed to Bruce Russell, from Polish Daily News (Oversize 10)
    - Krawiec, Walter. "In Bretton Woods" (European reconstruction), 10 Jan 1946; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Kuhn, Charles. "Always in the background" (threat of war), 1946; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Kuhn, Charles. "Yep, the days are getting shorter" (voter resentment against the Democrats), 1946; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Lantz, Walter. Color Woody Woodpecker animation cell, undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell from "Walter Lantz and Woody Woodpecker." (Oversize 10)
    - Lawton. "The hired gun" (Truman), undated (Oversize 10)
    - Levering, Albert. Untitled (parlor scene), 1911; pen and ink illustration (Oversize 16)
    - Lichty, George. "That settles it, Roscoe!... We're going on vacation right now while we still have something to come back to...", 23 Apr 1955; "Grin and Bear It" panel on do-it-yourselfers, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Little, Tom. "Something to do more than think about" (school enrollment), undated (Oversize 16)
    - Long, Scott. "Sales promotion" (Stalin), inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Loring, Paule. "Tender-hearted pop says no", undated (Oversize 10)
    - Loring, Paule. "We are prepared for the worst" (air raids on Japan), 14 Jun 1945 (Oversize 10)
    - Maples, Harold. "Courage boy" (Alaska statehood), undated (Oversize 10)
    - Maples, Harold. "Not much room left" (federal spending), undated (Oversize 10)
    - Maples, Harold. "This is going to be interesting" (labor racketeering), 1 Feb 1959 (Oversize 10)
    - Maples, Harold. "Will our dream boat get home?" (government spending), undated (Oversize 10)
    - Marcus, Ed. The 'blue' horizon" (Hitler's Russian offensive), 18 Oct 1942; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Mauldin, Bill. "Fallout" (Khrushchev), 1961; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Mauldin, Bill. Untitled sketch (G.I. Joe), circa 1945; pen and ink, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Maxwell, G.T. "But when he got up close...!" (a Roosevelt third term), circa 1940 (Oversize 10)
    - McGee, Ernie. Untitled (restaurants strip), undated (Oversize 16)
    - McNerney, Gene. Untitled illustration, undated; pen and ink, inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Eam. "Script.", undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 9)
    - McNerney, Gene. "Buy and buy and buy and let him pay and pay and pay", undated; Illustration for Liberty Magazine (Oversize 10)
    - Messner, Elmer. "A dangerous plaything" (Spanish Civil War), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Mullin, Willard. Untitled (neckwear), undated; color cartoon (Oversize 10)
    - Murphy, J.E. "Interned for forty days" (Lent), 24 Mar 1916; inscribed to A.M. Moore (Oversize 10)
    - Myers, Fred. Cartoon self-portrait, 7 May 1928; with note to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Nichols, Nick. Untitled strip, 1930; probably titled "Oh, boy, are we going to have fun!" (Oversize 10)
    - Nolley, Lance. "Samson and Delilah" (the Kellogg-Briand Pact), circa 1928 (Oversize 16)
    - Norris, L. "Don't mind 'er. She's just found out 'er sex can orbit in space and topple governments, all in one week.", 19 Jun 1963 (Oversize 10)
    - Opper, F. Untitled illustration, 10 Mar [no year]; pen and ink (Oversize 10)
    - Orr, Carey. "Head salesman reports to the general manager" (Soviet diplomacy), 21 Jan 1959; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Orr, Carey. "The old claim seems to be about played out" (bleak Republican future in 1931), inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Page, Grover. "Adolf has ceiling problems too" (Hitler), undated (Oversize 10)
    - Page, Grover. "High ball", 29 Dec 1943 (Oversize 10)
    - Page, Grover. "But what's holding up the secret weapon?" (German secret weapon), circa 1944 (Oversize 10)
    - Paprocki, Tom. "Flying high.", 1930; sports cartoon, inscribed to Bruce Russell. (Oversize 10)
    - Parrish, Joe. "The man who hitched his wagon to a star" (New Deal utopian schemes), 1936; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Pease, Lute. "The face of stone" (WPA strike), circa 1930s; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)
    - Pletcher, Eldon. "Strictly from hunger?" (Soviet agricultural failures), undated; inscribed to Bruce Russell (Oversize 10)